Change your fate.
Brave is a animation, adventure, comedy film directed by Mark Andrews.
In the mystical Scottish Highlands, Merida is the princess of a
kingdom ruled by King Fergus and Queen Elinor.
An unruly daughter and an accomplished archer, Merida one day defies a sacred
custom of the land and inadvertently brings turmoil to the kingdom.
In an attempt to set things right, Merida seeks out an eccentric
old Wise Woman and is granted an ill-fated wish.
Also figuring into Merida's quest — and serving as comic relief — are the kingdom's three lords: the
enormous Lord MacGuffin, the surly Lord Macintosh, and the disagreeable Lord Dingwall.
Merida (voice), played by Kelly Macdonald.
Elinor (voice), played by Emma Thompson.
Fergus (voice), played by Billy Connolly.
The Witch (voice), played by Julie Walters.
Lord Dingwall (voice), played by Robbie Coltrane.
Lord MacGuffin / Young MacGuffin (voice), played by Kevin McKidd.
Brave is a 2012 American animated fantasy adventure film produced by Pixar
Animation Studios and released by Walt Disney Pictures.
The film was directed by Mark Andrews and Brenda Chapman, co-directed by Steve Purcell, and produced by
Katherine Sarafian, with John Lasseter, Andrew Stanton, and Pete Docter serving as executive producers.
The story was written by Chapman, who also co-wrote the film's
screenplay with Andrews, Purcell, and Irene Mecchi.
The film stars the voices of Kelly Macdonald, Billy Connolly, Emma Thompson,
Julie Walters, Robbie Coltrane, Kevin McKidd, and Craig Ferguson.
Set in the Scottish Highlands, the film tells the story of Princess Merida of DunBroch (Macdonald) who defies
an age-old custom, causing chaos in the kingdom by expressing the desire not to be betrothed.
When Queen Elinor (Thompson), her mother, is turned into a bear, Merida must
look within herself and find the key to saving the kingdom.
Merida is the first character in the Disney
Princess line to be created by Pixar.
The film is also dedicated to Pixar chairman and Apple co-founder and
CEO Steve Jobs, who died before the film's release.
Brave is Pixar's first film with a female protagonist, and the first one
animated with a new proprietary animation system, called Presto.
Originally titled The Bear and the Bow, the film was first announced
in April 2008 alongside Up (2009) and Cars 2 (2011).
Chapman, who had just wrapped up work as a story artist on Cars (2006), drew
inspiration for the film's story from her relationship with her own daughter.
Co-directing with Andrews and Purcell, Chapman became Pixar's
first female director of a feature-length film.
To create the most complex visuals possible, Pixar completely rewrote
their animation system for the first time in 25 years.
Brave is the first film to use the Dolby Atmos sound format.
The filmmakers created three original tartan patterns
for three of the four clans in the film.
Patrick Doyle composed the film's musical score.
Brave premiered at the Seattle International Film Festival on June 10, 2012,
and was theatrically released in North America on June 22.
Receiving generally positive reviews, it was a box office success,
grossing $539 million against a $185 million budget.
The film won the Academy Award, the Golden Globe, and the
BAFTA Award for Best Animated Feature Film.
Preceding the feature theatrically was a short film
entitled La Luna, directed by Enrico Casarosa.
The film explores themes of witch, kingdom, scotland, rebel, bravery.
The tone is lighthearted.